whoishostingthis.com 2014-12-28

# WhoIsHostingThis.com Privacy Policy

**WhoIsHostingThis.com is operated by Quality Nonsense Ltd. Learn more aboutthe team behind the site, how to contact us & more in our 'about' section.**

Your privacy is extremely important to us. This policy sets out how WhoIsHostingThis.com uses and protects any information collected when you use this website. It’s worth a read, but if you’re short of time, here’s the most important stuff:

  * We won’t collect any personal information (eg. name, email address) without your explicit permission;
  * We won’t send you promotional emails unless you’ve double opted in
  * We will never share, sell or rent sensitive information about you without your permission (unless required to by UK law)
  * We have physical, electronic and managerial procedures to ensure your personal information is secure.

We hope it goes without saying that we will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully and in accordance with the UK Data Protection Act 1998. Above and beyond that, we will endeavour to use this information in a way that benefits you as a user.

When we ask you to provide information by which you can be identified when using this website, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Our privacy policy may change from time to time. We’ll do our best to let you know but please do check back periodically for updates.

## What Information We Collect

We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent. By ‘sensitive information’ we mean details like:

  * Your name
  * Your email address

We also use cookies to collect non-sensitive information about your use of the site. This is standard on almost any website nowadays and allows us to understand how visitors use the site: which pages are most popular, which bits don't work and so on.

## How We Use This Data

We only send you promotional emails if you have explicitly double opted-in. We do not sell, rent or share email addresses, and we never will. We will only share personal information when required by law (eg, if subpoenaed to do so).

We will only pass your data on to third parties if you have explicitly agree that we do so. For example: if you submit a [review](http://www.whoishostingthis.com/hosting-reviews/) which qualifies for a [free domain at Domain.com](http://www.whoishostingthis.com/free-domain/) in our promotion, we need to pass your details on to Register.com to have your prize sent out.

The reason we collect information like email addresses is to provide you with a better service. For example, we need some personal details to do the following:

  * To improve our service (eg, you now have the option to receive your search results by email in our hosting search tool)
  * Technical support (eg, if you are experiencing problems that we can't replicate)
  * User newsletters (you only receive this if you double opt-in to receive it)
  * To customise your user experience (eg, we can show your web hosts that match your requirements)

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website. Or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## Your IP Address

We may use your IP address for several reasons:

  * To gather traffic & user data using Google Analytics
  * To customise your user experience (eg, we can show your web hosts that match your requirements)

## Cookies

A cookie is a small file that asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site.

Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use cookies with various analytics & usalbity tools, such as:

  * Google Analytics
  * CrazyEgg.com
  * OpenX ad server
  * Clicktale.net

Cookies help us provide you with a better website for many reasons, such as allowing us to see which pages are popular or unpopular. A cookie does not give us access to your computer or any information about you, except data that you choose to share with us.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## External Links

Our website contains links to other websites. We do not have any control over the content or behaviour of external websites, so cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites. External sites are not governed by this privacy statement.

## Personal Information

If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to the address on our 'contact us' page.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us immediately. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

## Any Questions?

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please [contact us](http://www.whoishostingthis.com/contact/).
